<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <array name="visit_title">
        <item>Wawel Royal Castle</item>
        <item>The Kraków Cloth Hall</item>
        <item>Saint Mary\'s Church</item>
        <item>Kazimierz</item>
        <item>Juliusz Słowacki Theatre</item>
        <item>The Kraków Barbican</item>
        <item>St. Florian\'s Gate</item>
    </array>
    <array name="visit_body">
        <item>It is one of the largest Castels in Poland, represents nearly all European architectural
            styles of medieval, renaissance and baroque periods. The Wawel Royal Castle and the
            Wawel Hill constitute the most historically and culturally significant site in the
            country. In 1978 it was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site as part of the Historic
            Centre of Kraków. The Castle is now one of the country\'s premier art museums.</item>
        <item>It is one of the city\'s most recognizable icons. It is the central feature of the
            main market square in the Kraków Old Town (listed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site
            since 1978). It was once a major centre of international trade. Traveling merchants
            met there to discuss business and to barter. During its golden age in the 15th century,
            the hall was the source of a variety of exotic imports from the east – spices, silk,
            leather and wax – while Kraków itself exported textiles, lead, and salt from the
            Wieliczka Salt Mine. On the upper floor of the hall is the Sukiennice Museum division
            of the National Museum.</item>
        <item>It is a Brick Gothic church adjacent to the Main Market Square in Kraków, Poland. Built
            in the 14th century, its foundations date back to the early 13th century and serve as
            one of the best examples of Polish Gothic architecture. Standing 80 m (262 ft) tall,
            it is particularly famous for its wooden altarpiece carved by Veit Stoss (Wit Stwosz).
            On every hour, a trumpet signal—called the Hejnał mariacki—is played from the top of
            the taller of Saint Mary\'s two towers. The plaintive tune breaks off in mid-stream,
            to commemorate the famous 13th century trumpeter, who was shot in the throat while
            sounding the alarm before the Mongol attack on the city.</item>
        <item>It is a historical district of Kraków and Kraków Old Town, Poland. Since its
            inception in the fourteenth century to the early nineteenth century, Kazimierz was an
            independent city, a royal city of the Crown of the Polish Kingdom, located south of
            Kraków Old Town and separated by a branch of the Vistula river. For many centuries,
            Kazimierz was a place of coexistence and interpenetration of ethnic Polish and Jewish
            cultures, its north-eastern part of the district was historic Jewish, whose Jewish
            inhabitants were forcibly relocated in 1941 by the German occupying forces into the
            Krakow ghetto just across the river in Podgórze. Today Kazimierz is one of the major
            tourist attractions of Krakow and an important center of cultural life of the city.</item>
        <item>Erected in 1893, was modeled after some of the best European Baroque theatres such as
            the Paris Opera designed by Charles Garnier, and named after Polish poet Juliusz
            Słowacki in 1909. The Theatre became the birthplace of the theatrical concept of the
            Young Poland movement and was closely related to the rediscovery of Romantic drama as
            well as the premiere productions of plays by Polish national playwright Stanisław Wyspiański.</item>
        <item>A fortified outpost once connected to the city walls. It is a historic gateway leading
            into the Old Town of Kraków, Poland. The barbican is one of the few remaining relics of
            the complex network of fortifications and defensive barriers that once encircled the royal
            city of Kraków in the south of Poland. The Gothic-style barbican, built around 1498,
            is one of only three such fortified outposts still surviving in Europe, and the best
            preserved. It currently serves as a tourist attraction and venue for a variety of exhibitions.</item>
        <item>It is one of the best-known Polish Gothic towers, and a focal point of Kraków\'s Old
            Town. It was built about the 14th century as a rectangular Gothic tower of "wild stone",
            part of the city fortifications against Turkish attack. The Gate tower is 33.5 metres tall.
            The Baroque metal "helmet" that crowns the gate, constructed in 1660 and renovated in 1694,
            adds another metre to the height of the gate. The adjoining city walls and two additional,
            smaller towers had been preserved and today host street displays of amateur art available
            for purchase.</item>
    </array>
    <array name="visit_image">
        <item>@drawable/wawel</item>
        <item>@drawable/sukiennice</item>
        <item>@drawable/mariacki</item>
        <item>@drawable/kazimierz</item>
        <item>@drawable/slowacki</item>
        <item>@drawable/barbakan</item>
        <item>@drawable/florianska</item>
    </array>
    <array name="nature_title">
        <item>Planty Park</item>
        <item>Botanic Garden</item>
        <item>Kościuszko Mound</item>
        <item>Jordan Park</item>
    </array>
    <array name="nature_body">
        <item>It is one of the largest city parks in Kraków, Poland. It encircles the Stare Miasto
            (Old Town), where the Medieval city walls used to stand until the early 19th century.
            The park has an area of 21,000 square meters (5.2 acres) and a length of 4 kilometers
            (2.5 mi). It consists of a chain of thirty smaller gardens designed in varied styles
            and adorned with numerous monuments and fountains. The park forms a scenic walkway.</item>
        <item>It is a botanical garden, founded in 1783 in Kraków. It is located east of the
            Old Town (Stare Miasto) and occupies 9.6 hectares. It belongs to the Jagiellonian
            University and is classified as a historical location. Currently the plant collection
            contains approximately 5000 species and varieties from around the world. This total
            includes nearly 1,000 species of trees and shrubs, and more than 2,000 species and
            varieties of plants in greenhouses.</item>
        <item>Erected by Cracovians in commemoration of the Polish national leader Tadeusz
            Kościuszko, is an artificial mound modeled after Kraków\'s prehistoric mounds of
            Krak and Wanda. A serpentine path leads to the top, approx. 326 metres (1,070 ft)
            above sea level, with a panoramic view of the Vistula River and the city. It was
            completed in November 1823. The location selected for the monument was the natural
            Blessed Bronisława Hill (Polish: Wzgórze bł. Bronisławy), also known as Sikornik,
            situated in the western part of Kraków\'s Zwierzyniec District.</item>
        <item>It was established in 1889 as the first public playground in Kraków, Poland,
            and the first of its kind in Europe. It was equipped with exercise fixtures
            modeled after those of similar playgrounds in the United States. The park is
            located in Kraków\'s Błonia (municipal grasslands that had previously
            served as cattle pasture).Jordan Park was Dr. Henryk Jordan\'s biggest achievement,
            brought to completion with the help from the director of Kraków City Parks, Bolesław Malecki.</item>
    </array>
    <array name="nature_image">
        <item>@drawable/planty</item>
        <item>@drawable/botaniczny</item>
        <item>@drawable/kopiec</item>
        <item>@drawable/jordana</item>
    </array>
    <array name="museums_title">
        <item>Polish Aviation Museum</item>
        <item>The Museum of Municipal Engineering</item>
        <item>Oskar Schindler\'s Factory</item>
        <item>National Museum in Kraków</item>
        <item>Manggha</item>
        <item>Cricoteka</item>
    </array>
    <array name="museums_body">
        <item>It is a large museum of old aircraft and aircraft engines in Kraków, Poland. It is
            located at the site of the no-longer functional Kraków-Rakowice-Czyżyny Airport. This
            airfield, established by Austria-Hungary in 1912, is one of the oldest in the world.
            The museum opened in 1964, after the airfield closed in 1963. Has been scored as eighth
            world\'s best aviation museum by CNN. Several of the aircraft displayed are unique on the
            world scale, including sailplanes and some 100 aircraft engines.</item>
        <item>It is a municipal museum in Kraków, Poland; located at ul. św. Wawrzyńca 15 street
            in the centre of historical Kazimierz district. It was established in 1998 by the city,
            for the purpose of documenting and popularizing the history of the city engineering,
            transport as well as technological progress. It consists of several buildings housing
            early trams, buses and motorcycles, radios, industrial machinery and early means of
            production, as well as many educational aids and displays.</item>
        <item>Exhibition "Kraków under Nazi Occupation 1939–1945" is located in the former
            administrative building of Oskar Schindler\'s Enamel Factory at 4 Lipowa Street.
            The exhibition is primarily a story about Kraków and its inhabitants, both Polish
            and Jewish, during World War Two. It is also a story about Nazi Germans – the occupiers
            who arrived here on 6 September 1939, brutally disrupting Kraków\'s centuries-long
            history of Polish-Jewish relations. </item>
        <item>The Museum consists of 21 departments which are divided by art period; 11 galleries,
            2 libraries, and 12 conservation workshops. It holds some 780,000 art objects, spanning
            from classical archeology to modern art, with special focus on Polish painting. The Main
            Building features the newly renovated upper Gallery of the Twentieth Century Polish Art,
            one of the largest galleries of painting and sculpture from the late 19th century on in
            Poland, with most celebrated artwork by Jacek Malczewski, Leon Wyczółkowski, Włodzimierz
            Tetmajer; an extensive collection of works by Stanisław Wyspiański; and also, works by
            artists of the interwar and postwar periods: the Polish cubists, expressionists, colorists,
            the avant-garde of the 1930s, and representatives of New Directions from the 1960s.</item>
        <item>It is Museum of Japanese Art and Technology. In 1920, Feliks Jasieński—critic, writer
            and collector of art, whose penname was "Manggha"—donated his collection of artworks
            connected with Japan to the National Museum in Kraków. In 1987, Andrzej Wajda received
            a film award in Kyoto. He decided to donate the entire sum to build a brand new building
            in which to exhibit the entire collection. The building was designed by the Japanese
            architect Arata Isozaki, who donated the design to the foundation. Krzysztof Ingarden,
            J.Ewy and JET Atelier were collaborating architects on the Polish side. Manggha was
            opened on November 30, 1994.</item>
        <item>The Centre for the Documentation of the Art of Tadeusz Kantor was founded by the
            artist Tadeusz Kantor as early as in 1980; originally named the Centre of the Cricot
            2 Theatre. For almost ten years, the institution has been the cornerstone of Kantor\'s
            avant-garde theatre, as well as a \'living archive\' of his theatrical creation. The unique
            collection of Kantor\'s works is the basis of the activities of the Centre. The collection
            comprises several hundred objects and costumes from the Cricot 2 Theatre, Kantor/'s
            theoretical papers, drawings and design works, video records, and photographic
            documentation as well as thousands of reviews, journals and books.</item>
    </array>
    <array name="museums_image">
        <item>@drawable/lotnictwa</item>
        <item>@drawable/inzynieria</item>
        <item>@drawable/schindler</item>
        <item>@drawable/narodowe</item>
        <item>@drawable/manggha</item>
        <item>@drawable/critoteka</item>
    </array>
    <array name="events_title">
        <item>Wianki (Wreaths)</item>
        <item>Traditional Rękawka Festival</item>
        <item>The Great Dragon Parade</item>
        <item>Juwenalia</item>
        <item>Pierogi (Dumplings) Festival</item>
    </array>
    <array name="events_body">
        <item>An old Slavic custom whose roots date back to pre-Christian times, held during the
            spring/summer solstice when the night is shortest and the day longest. During this day
            the most important two were darkness and light. In the middle of the night the community
            of the Slavic settlement went to a secluded place, often an old cemetery. On the sacred
            spots huge bonfires were started and burnt till morning to accompany the songs, dances,
            and various revelry and frolics. At the culmination moment of the celebrations girls
            floated wreaths plaited of various herbs and flowers on the water, a symbols of virginity.
            Presently it has a form of mass picnic with musical concerts and fireworks, held at
            shore of Vistula river. </item>
        <item>Held at the Krakus Mound this festival transports you back in time. You will experience
            life in early-mediaeval settlements, learn about ancient crafts and admire knights armour
            and everyday costumes.  The steep slopes of the hill are the perfect vantage point for
            admiring the warriors clad in full armour running around the mound, and re-enacting
            historical battles.</item>
        <item>In Kraków there is a legend of the Wawel Dragon, a dreadful beast that devoured all
            the livestock and terrorised the city until a brave tailor fed it sulphur covered in
            sheepskin, causing the monster to drink and drink and drink until it burst into a
            million pieces. This colourful festival brings him to life with enormous puppets
            created by Teatr Groteska, as well as floats created by locals. Saturday night\'s
            spectacular extravaganza on the river, during which flying dragons battle it out
            to a backdrop of lasers, fireworks and music, is one of Kraków\'s absolute cultural
            highlights and not to be missed if you\'re in town.</item>
        <item>It is an annual higher education students holiday in Poland, usually celebrated in
            May, before the summer exams, sometimes also at the beginning of June. The first
            Juwenalia were celebrated in the 15th century in Cracow. Juwenalia start with a
            triumphant parade of colorfully dressed students. The participants march from a
            college\'s campus to city\'s main square, where in a symbolic gesture, the mayor of a
            city hands keys to the city\'s gates to the students. The three days are free from
            lectures and filled with concerts, parties, sports events as well as beer drinking.</item>
        <item>The festival presents one of the most famous item of Polish cuisine - the dumpling.
            The event will help you to get to know Polish tradition of cuisine better as well as to
            try out the specialties. Festival is usually celebrated at the Plac Szczepanski (Square)
            and Small Market Square, where several restaurants and food producers present their offers.
            There is always a lot to taste: many types of pierogi with different fillings, either
            cooked or fried with their crispy golden crust, as well as traditional oscypek cheese
            from the mountains.</item>
    </array>
    <array name="events_image">
        <item>@drawable/wianki</item>
        <item>@drawable/rekawka</item>
        <item>@drawable/smoki</item>
        <item>@drawable/juwenalia</item>
        <item>@drawable/pierogi</item>
    </array>
</resources>